<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ROOT>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>King Arthur is a legendary British leader of the late 5th and early 6th centuries, who, according to medieval histories and romances, led the defence of Britain against Saxon invaders in the early 6th century.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The details of Arthur's story are mainly composed of folklore and literary invention, and his historical existence is debated and disputed by modern historians.[2] The sparse historical background of Arthur is gleaned from various sources, including the Annales Cambriae, the Historia Brittonum, and the writings of Gildas. Arthur's name also occurs in early poetic sources such as Y Gododdin.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Arthur is a central figure in the legends making up the so-called Matter of Britain. The legendary Arthur developed as a figure of international interest largely through the popularity of Geoffrey of Monmouth's fanciful and imaginative 12th-century Historia Regum Britanniae (History of the Kings of Britain).</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In some Welsh and Breton tales and poems that date from before this work, Arthur appears either as a great warrior defending Britain from human and supernatural enemies or as a magical figure of folklore, sometimes associated with the Welsh Otherworld, Annwn.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Geoffrey depicted Arthur as a king of Britain who defeated the Saxons and established an empire over Britain, Ireland, Iceland, Norway and Gaul. Many elements and incidents that are now an integral part of the Arthurian story appear in Geoffrey's Historia.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The historical basis for the King Arthur legend has long been debated by scholars. One school of thought, citing entries in the Historia Brittonum (History of the Britons) and Annales Cambriae (Welsh Annals), sees Arthur as a genuine historical figure, a Romano-British leader who fought against the invading Anglo-Saxons sometime in the late 5th to early 6th century.
        </CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The creator of the familiar literary persona of Arthur was Geoffrey of Monmouth, with his pseudo-historical Historia Regum Britanniae (History of the Kings of Britain), written in the 1130s. The textual sources for Arthur are usually divided into those written before Geoffrey's Historia (known as pre-Galfridian texts, from the Latin form of Geoffrey, Galfridus) and those written afterwards, which could not avoid his influence.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>There is much written testimony about the fifth century in Britain. Some of it is contemporary, but, unfortunately, very little of it is indigenous to Britain. Almost all of it, at least in some points, is contradictory.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Any attempt, then, to pin down an exact chronology of the period is a speculative enterprise, at best. Britannia's "Arthurian Timeline" falls into that category, as well. No effort was made to adhere to any traditional dating schemes, except where there is firmly established documentation for them.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Arthur, it seems, is claimed as the King of nearly every Celtic Kingdom known. The 6th century certainly saw many men named Arthur born into the Celtic Royal families of Britain but, despite attempts to identify the great man himself amongst them, there can be little doubt that most of these people were only named in his honour.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Geoffrey of Monmouth recorded Arthur as a High-King of Britain. He was the son of his predecessor, Uther Pendragon and nephew of King Ambrosius.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Geoffrey of Monmouth recorded Arthur as a High-King of Britain. He was the son of his predecessor, Uther Pendragon and nephew of King Ambrosius.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Worried that Arthur would fall in battle, Merlin took the King to a magical lake where a mysterious hand thrust itself up from the water, holding aloft a magnificent sword.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Variously portrayed in literature, she is called the daughter of King Leodegrance (Lleudd-Ogrfan) of Cameliard by Malory, the daughter of King Ogrfan Gawr (the Giant) of Castell y Cnwclas (Knucklas Castle) by Welsh Tradition, the daughter of King Garlin of Galore by Germanic tradition, the daughter of a Roman noble by Geoffrey of Monmouth and wife of King Arthur by everyone.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Early mentions of Guinevere, in the Triads of the Island of Britain, give tantalising glimpses of her original relationship with Mordred: he is shown forcing his way into Arthur's Court, dragging the Queen from her throne and striking her, but the reasons why are unknown.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Guinevere is frequently abducted in Romance, sometimes by King Melwas of Somerset, sometimes by Mordred and sometimes by the marauding tribes from the north. She meets her end sometimes in a convent at Amesbury or Caerleon and sometimes she dies at the vengeful hand of Lancelot.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Many elements and incidents that are now an integral part of the Arthurian story appear in Geoffrey's Historia, including Arthur's father Uther Pendragon, the wizard Merlin, Arthur's wife Guinevere, the sword Excalibur, Arthur's conception at Tintagel, his final battle against Mordred at Camlann and final rest in Avalon. The 12th-century French writer Chrétien de Troyes, who added Lancelot and the Holy Grail to the story, began the genre of Arthurian romance that became a significant strand of medieval literature.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The Name "Excalibur" was first used for King Arthur's sword by the French Romancers. It was not the famous "Sword in the Stone" (which broke in battle), but a second sword acquired by the King through the intercession of his druidic advisor, Merddyn (Merlin).</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Worried that Arthur would fall in battle, Merlin took the King to a magical lake where a mysterious hand thrust itself up from the water, holding aloft a magnificent sword.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Worried that Arthur would fall in battle, Merlin took the King to a magical lake where a mysterious hand thrust itself up from the water, holding aloft a magnificent sword.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>arthur</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The earliest Arthurian stories give the name of King Arthur's sword as Caladfwlch, a Welsh word derived from Calad-Bolg meaning "Hard Lightning". Later it developed to become the Caliburn of Geoffrey and Monmouth and finally the Frenchified Excalibur that we know today.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Was a warrior king of the Greek city-state of Sparta. He led the Spartan forces during the Second Persian War and is remembered for his heroic death at the Battle of Thermopylae. Leonidas was the third son of Anaxandridas II of Sparta.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>According to Herodotus, Leonidas' mother was his father's niece and had been barren for so long that the ephors, the five annually elected administrators of the Spartan constitution, tried to prevail upon King Anaxandridas to set aside his wife and take another. Anaxandridas refused, claiming his wife was blameless, whereupon the ephors agreed to allow him to take a second wife without setting aside his first.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Anaxandridas died in 520 BC,[5] and Cleomenes succeeded to the throne sometime between then and 516 BC.[6] Dorieus was so outraged that the Spartans had preferred his half-brother over himself that he found it impossible to remain in Sparta. He made one unsuccessful attempt to set up a colony in Africa and, when this failed, sought his fortune in Sicily, where after initial successes he was killed.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Leonidas was clearly heir to the Agiad throne and a full citizen (homoios) at the time of the Battle of Sepeia against Argos (c. 494 BC). Likewise, he was a full citizen when the Persians sought submission from Sparta and met with vehement rejection in or around 492/491 BC. </CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT> His elder brother the king had already been deposed on grounds of purported insanity, and had fled into exile when Athens sought assistance against the First Persian invasion of Greece, that ended at Marathon (490 BC).</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In August 480 BC, Leonidas went out to meet Xerxes' army at Thermopylae with a small force of 300 men, where he was joined by forces from other Greek city-states, who put themselves under his command to form an army of 14,000 strong.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Whatever the reason Sparta's own contribution was just 300 Spartiates (accompanied by their attendants and probably perioikoi auxiliaries), the total force assembled for the defense of the pass of Thermopylae came to something between four and seven thousand Greeks. They faced a Persian army who had invaded from the north of Greece under Xerxes I.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Xerxes waited four days to attack, hoping the Greeks would disperse. Finally, on the fifth day the Persians attacked. Leonidas and his men repulsed the Persians' frontal attacks for the fifth and sixth days, killing roughly 20,000 of the enemy troops and losing about 2,500 of their own.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The Persian elite unit known to the Greeks as "the Immortals" was held back, and two of Xerxes' brothers (Abrocomes and Hyperanthes) died in battle.[14] On the seventh day (August 11), a Malian Greek traitor named Ephialtes led the Persian general Hydarnes by a mountain track to the rear of the Greeks.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The King would have thought it wise to preserve those Greek troops for future battles against the Persians, but he knew that the Spartans could never abandon their post on the battlefield. The soldiers who stayed behind were to protect their escape against the Persian cavalry. </CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Of the small Greek force, attacked from both sides, all were killed except for the Thebans, who surrendered. Leonidas was killed, but the Spartans retrieved his CONTENT and protected it. Herodotus says that Xerxes' orders were to have Leonidas' head cut off and put on a stake and his CONTENT crucified.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Leonidas was the Spartan king who famously led a small band of Greek allies at the Battle of Thermopylae in 480 BCE where the Greeks valiantly defended the pass through which the Persian king Xerxes sought to invade Greece with his massive army.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Ultimately, Leonidas and his men were wiped out, but they bought the Greek city-states valuable time and gave an inspirational example, not only of what Greek hoplites could achieve against the invading forces but also of the price Greeks were willing to pay to maintain their freedom from foreign oppression.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Following Xerxes' proposed land invasion of mainland Greece in 480 BCE Leonidas was selected to lead a small contingent of Spartan hoplites - some 300 hand-picked men with male heirs - to defend the pass of Thermopylae and hold the invading force until more troops could be mustered. </CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Thermopylae, 150 km north of Athens, was an excellent choice as the point to defend Greece, as there mountains rolled down into the sea leaving only a narrow pass along the coast.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>With Leonidas leading from the front and the hoplites fighting in their tight phalanx formation, they took full advantage of their superior armour and weapons and managed to hold the vast Persian army for two days. However, betrayed by a local shepherd who told the Persians of a mountain path which would allow them to get behind the Greek lines, things looked grim for the defenders.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Ultimately, though, the Greek forces were wiped out to a man and Apollo’s oracle at Delphi had been proved right when she had stated that either Sparta or one of her kings must fall.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Leonidas’ son Pleistarchus became king on his father’s death but due to his young age Pausanius acted as regent. The Greeks, within a year, gained revenge for Thermopylae with victories at Salamis and Plataea; the latter even led by Pausanius, nephew of Leonidas. Xerxes' invasion was emphatically rebuffed and those who fell at Thermopylae were not forgotten.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>A monument was set up at the site with the words of Simonedes’ epitaph stating: ‘go tell the Spartans, you who read: We took their orders and here lie dead’. A stone lion was also placed in memory of Leonidas and his men.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>leonidas</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In ancient art, Leonidas is quite possibly the subject of a surviving marble statue from the acropolis of Sparta, 490-480 BCE. Resplendent in a crested Corinthian helmet, his face, which would have had inlaid eyes, depicts the grim determination for which the fallen king became a legend.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Scottish celebrity chef, restaurateur, and television personality. His restaurants have been awarded 15 Michelin stars in total and currently hold 14.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT> Ramsay's signature restaurant, Restaurant Gordon Ramsay in Chelsea, London has held 3 Michelin stars since 2001. Ramsay is known for presenting TV programmes about competitive cookery and food, such as the British series Hell's Kitchen, The F Word, Ramsay's Kitchen Nightmares along with the American versions of Hell's Kitchen, Kitchen Nightmares and MasterChef.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Gordon Ramsay was born on 8 November 1966[1] in Johnstone, Renfrewshire, Scotland,[6] and raised in Stratford-upon-Avon, Warwickshire, England, from the age of 5.[7] Ramsay is the second of four children</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In the early 1980s, he worked as a commis chef at the Wroxton House Hotel then ran the kitchen and 60-seat dining room at the Wickham Arms, until his sexual relationship with the owner's wife made the situation difficult.[21] Ramsay then moved to London, where he worked in a series of restaurants until being inspired to work for the temperamental Marco Pierre White at Harvey's.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Upon his return to London in 1993, Ramsay was offered the position of head chef (under chef-patron Pierre Koffmann) at the Three Michelin starred La Tante Claire in Chelsea. Shortly thereafter, Marco Pierre White re-entered his life, offering to set him up with a head chef position and 10% share in the Rossmore, owned by White's business partners.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The restaurant was renamed Aubergine and went on to win its first Michelin star fourteen months later. In 1997, Aubergine won its second Michelin star.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Ramsay opened his own restaurant in Chelsea, Restaurant Gordon Ramsay, with the help of his father-in-law, Chris Hutcheson. The restaurant gained its third Michelin star in 2001, making Ramsay the first Scot to achieve that feat.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>From his first restaurant, Ramsay's empire has expanded rapidly, next opening Petrus, then Amaryllis in Glasgow (which he was later forced to close) and later Gordon Ramsay at Claridge's. Restaurants at the Dubai Creek and Connaught hotels followed, the latter branded with his protégé Angela Hartnett's name.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>However, in February 2012 Danny Lavy — the owner of the restaurant — announced the restaurant was disassociating itself from Ramsay, citing a lack of involvement and understanding on Ramsay's part.[27] In 2013, the restaurant closed. Along the way, he also hired his friend and matre'd Jean-Philippe Susilovic, who works in London at Petrus, and also appears on the TV show Hell's Kitchen.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Opened in 1998, Restaurant Gordon Ramsay was Ramsay’s first solo restaurant, located at Royal Hospital Road, London. In 2001, it was voted Top Restaurant in the UK in the London Zagat Survey and was awarded its third Michelin star, making Gordon Ramsay the first Scottish chef to win three Michelin stars.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>On July 2006, Ramsay won the Catey award for "Independent Restaurateur of the Year", becoming only the third person to have won three Catey awards, the biggest awards of the UK hospitality industry. Ramsay's two previous Catey awards were in 1995 (Newcomer of the Year) and 2000 (Chef of the Year). The other two triple-winners are Michel Roux, and Jacquie Pern.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>n 2004, Ramsay appeared in two British television series. Ramsay's Kitchen Nightmares aired on Channel 4, and saw the chef troubleshooting failing restaurants over a one week period. This series ran its fifth series in 2007. Hell's Kitchen was a reality show, which aired on ITV1, and saw Ramsay attempt to train ten British celebrities to be chefs, as they ran a restaurant on Brick Lane which opened to the public for the two-week duration of the show.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Scottish by birth, Gordon Ramsay was brought up in Stratford-upon-Avon, England. His dedication and natural talent led him to train with some of the world’s leading chefs, such as Albert Roux and Marco Pierre White in London, and Guy Savoy and Joël Robuchon in France.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In 1993 Gordon became chef of Aubergine in London, which within three years, was awarded two Michelin stars. In 1998, at the age of 31, Ramsay set up his first wholly owned and namesake restaurant, Restaurant Gordon Ramsay, which quickly received the most prestigious accolade in the culinary world – three Michelin stars.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In 1993 Ramsay took the reins of the newly opened Aubergine. Within three years, he had earned two Michelin stars. After a breakup with the restaurant’s backers, Ramsay left Aubergine, taking his staff with him.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Gordon Ramsay is known as the bete noir of the cooking world, a foul mouthed perfectionist who doesn’t suffer fools gladly - as famously recorded in his treatment of celebrities in the hugely successful TV shows ‘Hell’s Kitchens’ and ‘Ramsay’s Kitchen Nightmares’ .</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Five years later Gordon joined the famous Maxim’s restaurant in London as Chef de partie, eventually followed by a year at ‘Harvey’s’ Marco Pierre White’s south London restaurant. Still only in his twenties, Gordon moved to Le Gavroche to work alongside the eminent Albert Roux.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The master chef in the making soon realised he needed first hand experience of the intricacies of classic French cooking. In 1990 he moved to France where he spent three years in the kitchens of Guy Savoy and Joel Robuchon.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>n what became ‘water cooler’ television, ‘Ramsey’s Hell’s Kitchen’ saw the volatile chef give a variety of micro-celebrities a memorable tongue-lashing. Ramsey branded the celebrity chefs a ‘bunch of whingers’ and complained to the press that most of the stars ‘hadn’t done a day’s work in their lives’</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>ramsay</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Gordon lives with his wife Tana and children in South London. He regularly jogs home from work late at night after a long shift in his central London restaurants.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Is a fictional character in the Star Trek media franchise.[1] First portrayed by Leonard Nimoy in the original Star Trek series, Spock also appears in the animated Star Trek series, a two-part episode of Star Trek: The Next Generation, eight of the Star Trek feature films, and numerous Star Trek books, comics, and video games.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In the 2009 film Star Trek and its 2013 sequel Star Trek Into Darkness, Nimoy reprised his role alongside Zachary Quinto, who played a younger, alternate-universe version of the character, and Jacob Kogan playing Spock as a child.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Spock serves aboard the starship Enterprise, as science officer and first officer, and later as commanding officer of two iterations of the vessel. Spock's mixed human-Vulcan heritage serves as an important plot element in many of the character's appearances.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Along with Captain James T. Kirk and Dr. Leonard "Bones" McCoy, he is one of the three central characters in the original Star Trek series and its films.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>After retiring from Starfleet, Spock serves as a Federation ambassador, contributing toward the détente between the Federation and the Klingon Empire. In his later years, he serves as Federation ambassador to the Romulan Star Empire and becomes involved in the ill-fated attempt to save Romulus from a supernova.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The character was initially depicted as the USS Enterprise's science officer for the original pilot, "The Cage" (1964). Although "The Cage" did not air, Spock's eleven years of service under the command of Captain Christopher Pike are referred to and depicted in "The Menagerie" (1966) and other episodes.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The character's first broadcast appearance is in "The Man Trap" (1966), which introduces him as the ship's science officer and first officer under Captain James T. Kirk (William Shatner).[4] Star Trek depicts a "troika" of Spock, Kirk, and Doctor Leonard McCoy (DeForest Kelley); while McCoy often acts as Kirk's conscience.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Spock is no longer in Starfleet, having resigned and returned home to pursue the Vulcan discipline of Kolinahr. Spock is unable to complete the Kolinahr ritual after he senses the coming of V'ger, and rejoins Starfleet to aid the Enterprise crew in their mission.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT> In the film's final scene, he joins the crew of the newly commissioned USS Enterprise-A under Kirk's command.[1] In Star Trek V: The Final Frontier (1989), Spock and the Enterprise crew confront the renegade Sybok.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In the film's flashback (set 19 years after the events of "Unification", and as depicted in the comic miniseries Star Trek: Countdown[3]), Ambassador Spock (Nimoy) promises the Romulans he will use Vulcan technology to save them from a rogue supernova that threatens to destroy their Empire. </CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Stranded in the alternate past, the prime version of Spock helps alternate, younger versions of himself and Kirk (Zachary Quinto and Chris Pine, respectively) thwart Nero's attempt to destroy the Federation.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In Star Trek Into Darkness, Spock Prime is described as living on 'New Vulcan' while the younger Spock remains aboard the Enterprise struggling with the loss of his homeworld, as well as his relationships with Uhura and Captain Kirk.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Spock was born in 2230, in the city of Shi'Kahr on the planet Vulcan. His father is well-known Vulcan ambassador Sarek and his mother is Amanda Grayson, a human teacher. Serving as an outstanding Starfleet officer for decades and later as an ambassador, Spock was probably the most famous Vulcan-Human hybrid in history.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Spock got into an argument with his father when he chose the career of Starfleet service instead of the Vulcan Science Academy. Spock graduated from Starfleet Academy in 2251. As a young lieutenant he served as science officer on board the U.S.S. Enterprise (NCC-1701) under the command of Captain Christopher Pike. In 2254 he was a witness of Pike's capture by the inhabitants of Talos IV.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>After the end of the five-year mission Spock underwent the Kolinahr training on Vulcan, to achieve total emotional supression. He returned to the Enterprise in 2273 when it confronted the V'ger entity.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>On a training mission that turned into a real mission under Admiral Kirk in 2285 they went in search of the fate of the top secret "Genesis Device" and came under fire from old nemesis Khan.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Kirk and crew spring McCoy and illegally head to the Genesis Planet in a stolen Enterprise to find a regenerated Spock and angry Klingons who like to shoot at them.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In 2286 Spock, while still not whole, joins with the Enterprise crew in their stolen Klingon ship and returns to Earth for a court martial trial only to find the Earth under attack by a probe that is looking for extinct humpback whales.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>While Spock and Sarek have always had something of a strained relationship due to the emotion-less nature of Vulcan society, when Spock chose to enlist in Starfleet against Sarek's wishes, it caused a major rift between them.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>spock</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Spock was certified as a Starfleet Computer Specialist, and was soon assigned to the U.S.S. Enterprise where he served as the Chief Science Officer under Captain Christopher Pike for eleven years. When Pike was promoted to Fleet Captain, Spock remained aboard the Enterprise as First Officer under the ships succeeding Captain, James Kirk.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Was the leader of the Soviet Union from the mid-1920s until his death in 1953.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Among the Bolshevik revolutionaries who took part in the Russian Revolution of 1917, Stalin was appointed general secretary of the party's Central Committee in 1922. He subsequently managed to consolidate power following the 1924 death of Vladimir Lenin through suppressing Lenin's criticisms (in the postscript of his testament) and expanding the functions of his role, all the while eliminating any opposition.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>By the late 1920s, he was the unchallenged leader of the Soviet Union. He remained general secretary until the post was abolished in 1952, concurrently serving as the Premier of the Soviet Union from 1941 onward.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Under Stalin's rule, the concept of "socialism in one country" became a central tenet of Soviet society. He replaced the New Economic Policy introduced by Lenin in the early 1920s with a highly centralised command economy, launching a period of industrialization and collectivization that resulted in the rapid transformation of the USSR from an agrarian society into an industrial power.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The initial upheaval in agriculture disrupted food production and contributed to the catastrophic Soviet famine of 1932–1933, known as the Holodomor in Ukraine. Later, in a period that lasted from 1936 to 1939, Stalin instituted a campaign against alleged enemies within his regime, called the Great Purge, in which hundreds of thousands were executed. </CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Germany later violated the agreement and launched a massive invasion of the Soviet Union in June 1941. Despite heavy human and territorial losses, Soviet forces managed to halt the Nazi incursion after the decisive Battles of Moscow and Stalingrad.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>After defeating the Axis powers on the Eastern Front, the Red Army captured Berlin in May 1945, effectively ending the war in Europe for the Allies.[5][6] The Soviet Union subsequently emerged as one of two recognized world superpowers, the other being the United States.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Stalin led the Soviet Union through its post-war reconstruction phase, which saw a significant rise in tension with the Western world that would later be known as the Cold War. During this period, the USSR became the second country in the world to successfully develop a nuclear weapon, as well as launching the Great Plan for the Transformation of Nature in response to another widespread famine and the Great Construction Projects of Communism.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Stalin played a decisive role in engineering the 1921 Red Army invasion of Georgia, following which he adopted particularly hardline, centralist policies towards Soviet Georgia. This led to the Georgian Affair of 1922 and other repressions.[18][19] Stalin's actions in Georgia created a rift with Lenin, who believed that all the Soviet states should stand equal.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The Northern Expedition in China became a point of contention over foreign policy by Stalin and Trotsky. Stalin wanted the Communist Party of China to ally itself with the Nationalist Kuomintang, rather than attempt to implement a communist revolution.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>The eastern part of Poland, Latvia, Estonia, Finland and part of Romania were recognized as parts of the Soviet sphere of influence,[144] with Lithuania added in a second secret protocol in September 1939.[145] Stalin and Ribbentrop traded toasts on the night of the signing discussing past hostilities between the countries.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>On 1 September 1939, the German invasion of its agreed upon portion of Poland started World War II.[142] On 17 September the Red Army invaded eastern Poland and occupied the Polish territory assigned to it by the Molotov-Ribbentrop Pact, followed by co-ordination with German forces in Poland.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>After Stalin declared that he was going to "solve the Baltic problem", by June 1940, Lithuania, Latvia and Estonia were merged into the Soviet Union, after repressions and actions therein brought about the deaths of over 160,000 citizens of these states.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>After this campaign, Stalin took actions to bolster the Soviet military, modify training and improve propaganda efforts in the Soviet military.[154] In June 1940, Stalin directed the Soviet annexation of Bessarabia and northern Bukovina, proclaiming this formerly Romanian territory part of the Moldavian Soviet Socialist Republic. But in annexing northern Bukovina, Stalin had gone beyond the agreed limits of the secret protocol.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>On 6 May, Stalin replaced Molotov as Premier of the Soviet Union. Although Stalin had been the de facto head of government for a decade and a half, he had concluded relations with Nazi Germany had deteriorated to such an extent that he needed to deal with the problem as de jure head of government as well.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>During the early morning of 22 June 1941, Adolf Hitler broke the pact by implementing Operation Barbarossa, the German invasion of Soviet held territories and the Soviet Union that began the war on the Eastern Front.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>Already in autumn 1940 Stalin received a warning of the Dutch Communist Party, via the network of the Red Orchestra, that Hitler was preparing for a winter war by letting construct thousands of snow landing gears for the Junkers Ju 52 transport planes.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT> Although Stalin had received warnings from spies and his generals, he felt that Germany would not attack the Soviet Union until Germany had defeated Britain. In the initial hours after the German attack commenced, Stalin hesitated, wanting to ensure that the German attack was sanctioned by Hitler, rather than the unauthorized action of a rogue general.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>While the Germans pressed forward, Stalin was confident of an eventual Allied victory over Germany. In September 1941, Stalin told British diplomats that he wanted two agreements: (1) a mutual assistance/aid pact and (2) a recognition that, after the war, the Soviet Union would gain the territories in countries that it had taken pursuant to its division of Eastern Europe with Hitler in the Molotov–Ribbentrop Pact.</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
    <ENTITY>
        <LABEL>stalin</LABEL>
        <CONTENT>In 1942, Hitler shifted his primary goal from an immediate victory in the East, to the more long-term goal of securing the southern Soviet Union to conquer oil fields vital to a long-term German war effort.[174] In July 1942, Hitler praised the efficiency of the Soviet military industry and Stalin</CONTENT>
    </ENTITY>
</ROOT>